Santiago Lozano Sandino

Statistician and Data Analyst

Personal Information and Contact

Name: Santiago Lozano Sandino

Nationality: Colombian

e-mail: lozsandino@gmail.com
Cell/WhatsApp: +57 310 514 8811

Profile

I have an MSc in statistics and a bachelor's in economics. I have a solid quantitative background, deep knowledge about R Programming Language, which I've been using for over three years, and experience with other programming languages and applications such as Python, C, Stata and Visual Basic. Furthermore, I have experience in computational statistics, statistical analysis, Bayesian inference, exploratory data analysis, statistical modelling and data mining, among other fields. I'm an autonomous person, curious, proactive and self-taught, eager to learn and share my knowledge with others.

Education

Master of Science in Statistics (February, 2016 - January, 2018):

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile (Santiago, Chile).

- Relevant courses: Bayesian Inference, Advanced Computational Statistics, Exploratory and Computational Methods for Statistics.
- Degree project: Constrained Markov Chains: An Application for Melody Generation.
- Other relevant works: A Semiparametirc Poisson Autoregressive Model Applied to Vehicle Theft in Bogotá.
- Assistant-lecturer of course Linear Models, under the supervision of professor Reinaldo Arellano.

Bachelor's degree in Economics (August, 2008 - March, 2013):

Universidad de los Andes (Bogotá, Colombia).

- Relevant courses: Applied Research Seminar, Econometrics, Probability and Statistics.
- Degree project: Diffusion of Violence in Mexico: Spatial Analysis of Drug Related Violence.

Professional Experience

Ministerio de Justicia y del Derecho, Colombia (October, 2014 - December, 2015):

Advisor.

- Data analysis of crime related information.
- Promoting the use of statistics for decision-making within the organization.
- Instructor of a short introductory course about R Programming Language.

Talent Partner Consulting, Colombia (April, 2014 - August, 2014):

Consultant.

- Brief project about labor market and human management.
- Survey analysis and technical support writing the Visual Basic code necessary to perform such analysis.

Econometría Consultores, Colombia (April, 2013 - December, 2013):

Consultant.

- Several projects related to socio-economic and educational issues, which involved statistical analysis.
- Data analysis and modelling using Stata and Excel.

Skills

Software: R, Python, Excel, SQL, Git, GitHub, C, LaTeX, HTML, CSS and Stata. Languages: Spanish (native), English (advanced level), Portuguese (basic level).

Webpages

Personal and Portfolio: <u>lozsandino.github.io/profile</u>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/lozsandino/

GitHub: github.com/lozsandino

References

Reinaldo Arellano Valle (Professor – Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile):

e-mail: reivalle@mat.uc.cl

Claudia Vela Díaz (Immediate Supervisor – Ministerio de Justicia y del Derecho):

e-mail: claudia.vela@minjusticia.gov.co

Beatriz Aristizabal (Manager – Talent Partner Consulting):

e-mail: baristizabal@talentpartner.com.co